After you.
没事 您先吃 您先吃
You are the creator.
你是原创
You flattered me.
不不不
I saw you
我就是在你办公室
eat instant noodles in your office.
看你吃那泡面
I was mouthwatering.
给我馋的呀
I've eaten too much good food.
我这大鱼大肉吃多了
I'd like to taste
我也想尝尝
the food I ate in the college dorm.
这大学宿舍的味道
Come on!
来来来
It's okay.
不不不
Here comes mine.
来了 来了 来了
Is it the same?
是吧
Indeed it is.
还真是一样
When you studied abroad,
您在国外留学的时候
did you eat instant noodles in the dorm?
在宿舍也吃方便面啊
Yeah, we were strapped
我们在国外留学的时候
back that time.
都是穷学生
It was a great treat
能吃碗泡面的
to get a bowl of instant noodles.
那就是天大的享受啊
Yeah, right.
是啊 是是是
Would you like
要不要再来点酒
a drink?
喝点
I'll pass, thanks.
不不不
Actually,
那个
I rarely drink.
其实我平时不太喝酒
Once I've finished this bowl of noodles,
我吃完这碗面
I'll head upstairs to work.
我就上楼去工作了
Understood.
也是
You're on your own now,
你现在也是一个人
single
也算是
once more.
实实在在的光棍了
Mr. Zhou,
周总
I'll
我离婚的这个事呢
inform all investors
我会主动地
of my divorce.
告知所有的投资人
It won't
不会因为我个人的婚变
cause shareholding changes
影响到我们公司
of our company.
股权的变化
It won't.
不会
Being single has its advantages:
单身挺好的
you'll have high work efficiency
工作效率高
and be well-suited for entrepreneurship.
适合创业
We investors
我们投资人
favor startup founders
就喜欢你这种
like you,
背水一战的
who cut off all means of retreat.
创业公司老板
Agree.
是啊
Aside from
我现在除了我的蓝海
Blue Ocean,
也没有什么
there's nothing left to distract me.
可让我分心的了
But as I see,
但是据我
those who just get divorced
对身边的这些离异的
or become single
或者单身的人士的观察
are prone to
人刚一单身
emotional instability,
尤其是被分手
especially the one being dumped.
容易情绪不稳定
They'll frequently
经常会出现这种
feel lonely
突然之间
all of a sudden,
会感到孤单寂寞
Or,
或者
they'll have an emotional breakdown.
情绪突然崩溃
Mr. Yu, do you have
于总 我不知道你现在
this sort of feeling?
有没有这个症状
Nope.
没有
Definitely not.
我绝对没有
I think
我认为我自己是一个
I'm a middle-aged man
情绪非常稳定的
with emotional stability.
中年男人
Anyhow, I must offer you a word of caution:
但我得给你提个忠告啊
refrain from drowning sorrows in alcohol,
不要再借酒消愁了
and particularly from cozying up to strangers
尤其不要在酒吧
at bars.
跟不认识的人套近乎
Yeah, right.
是是是
Otherwise, you'll find yourself in a rather awkward situation
不然第二天酒醒过来
when you sober up the next day.
你说多尴尬啊
Yeah, yeah, exactly.
是是 没错没错
I've got a lot of experience
我呢
in being single.
单身经验比较丰富
If anything bothers you,
有什么想不开的
I'm all ears.
随时找我聊
Thanks, I will.
好的 好的
Let's eat noodles.
吃面
Okay.
吃面 吃面
Here he goes again.
又开始了
Won't it stop?
怎么没完没了的
I can't bear it a moment longer.
受不了了 受不了了
Why does your little brother keep crying?
你弟怎么一直哭呀
That's enough,
不行 不行
I can't take it anymore.
我实在受不了了
I am leaving.
我得走了
Wait, wait!
等等等 等会儿 等会儿
Stay with me a little longer.
再陪我一会儿
I haven't finished my homework yet.
我作业没写完
Please!
陪我
Stop it!
打住
I'll talk to him.
我去跟他说
Wait here for me.
在这儿等着我啊
Stop crying!
别哭啦
Haowen,
浩文
this is the feast you mentioned?
这就是你跟我说的
Are you serious?
大餐啊
Lin,
姐夫
I just don't wanna see you toil
我不是不舍得你在家
in the stove at home.
守着那个灶台累嘛
You think we teachers
你是觉得我
are easily fooled,
读书人好欺负
and that we has never enjoyed a feast?
没吃过大餐 是不是
Come on, it's so good to eat out.
出来多好啊
Feel the air, the environment,
你看这空气 这环境
and the river gushing in the distance.
远处滔滔不绝的江水
This place is popular
这都是现在年轻人
among the young.
全来的地方
It's great!
可好了
But still this has nothing to do with a feast.
那跟大餐什么关系呀
I bet this place will be the new location
我跟你说这个地儿
of a One-Michelin Starred restaurant
就是将来
in the future.
米其林一星选的新址
Enough, you were bragging.
行啦 你就吹吧
I know it.
我知道
Come on, Lin.
来 姐夫
You're caring about me, aren't you?
心疼我 是不是
I'll
我就在这儿
make do with it.
凑合凑合吃吧
Too bad there're so many dishes at home.
可惜了家里那么多菜
They'll
明天
become leftovers tomorrow.
就隔夜了
They won't go bad in the fridge.
放到冰箱坏不了
Lin,
姐夫
I got some tonic for Meng'an.
我刚才给姐拿了点补品
Mom said she has entered
妈说她那个
menopause earlier than expected.
更年期提前了
Yeah.
对
It's all right.
没事
It's just a minor problem.
小毛病
Minor problem?
什么小毛病
That's a serious matter.
这可真不是小毛病
Premature menopause?
更年期提前
She is not that old
姐才多大点岁数
and even younger than me.
还没我大呢
It's too bad!
这不可以的
She's to do body conditioning in time.
要赶紧调
Listen, Lin,
我跟你说 姐夫
I know lots of experienced doctors of TCM.
我认识好多老中医
I'll recommend you some of them.
我赶紧给你找关系
Seriously.
真的
The sooner the better.
早点调 早点好
You know, Mr. Li is my business partner.
跟我合作那个老李
His wife is 47 years old,
他老婆四十七岁
yet with the same problem.
也是有问题
So she made efforts to do body conditioning.
自己调调调 身体调好
Guess what?
你猜怎么着
She gave birth to a second baby!
生一二胎
Isn't it amazing?
厉害吧
You're so excited that
你激动个啥呀
that your chopsticks got dropped.
筷子都飞出去了
Of course, I'm excited.
我当然激动了
You'd better try hard
生二胎啊
to have a second child.
姐夫 得加油
I'm telling you,
我跟你讲
if anyone should have a second child,
这事
it's definitely you.
最该生二胎的就是你
We are the same.
咱俩一样
I love kids.
我就喜欢孩子
I like having a second child.
我就喜欢有二胎
What's your opinion?
你觉着呢
Don't you want a second child?
你不考虑啊
No need.
我考虑什么呀
We cannot afford to have it.
我们没有这个精力
You've got time and money.
你有钱 有闲
You can just have a second child.
你们生就行了
Lin,
姐夫
I don't agree with you.
此言差矣
Whether or not to have children
生不生孩子
is unrelated to wealth or leisure time.
跟有钱有闲没关系
When we were kids,
我们小的时候
my family had to struggle to make ends meet.
那家里穷得丁零当啷
Yet
那
the neighbors
左邻右舍的好多孩子
raised so many kids,
那家里生几个啊
with three or four children in the family.
三个四个
There was a classmate in our class
我们班同学
whose family had five children.
还有五个的呢
How pathetic I was then.
那会儿我多可怜啊
My mom
我妈带着我
was widowed but had to bring me up.
孤儿寡母的
My father passed away during my childhood.
父亲走得早
I just wished
就希望有个
to have
哥哥姐姐
some siblings.
或者弟弟妹妹的
If something happened,
有个事
they would support you.
还有个人照应
So I was so lonely back then.
太孤独了
So I'd been begging
我就一天老求着心心
and coaxing Xin
哄着心心
into giving birth
我就让心心给我
to a second baby.
生一个二胎
Then she really got pregnant.
我们家心心争气
She loves me
我们家心心爱我
and I love her, too.
我也爱她
With excellent genes
你这么好的基因
and good looks,
长得这么帅
it would be a shame not having a second child.
你不生可惜啦
When is the due date
你们家心心
of Xin?
什么时候生啊
Soon.
快了
Lin,
姐夫
Cheers.
来
Your father passed away early.
你是 父亲走得早
So did my dad.
我也是
You were raised by your elder sister.
你是姐拉扯大
While I by my mom.
我是我妈
You know,
咱俩真的是
if we both have a second child,
如果都有个二胎
then both Yunjie
云阶有个弟弟妹妹
and Xiongxiong
我们家熊熊
could have a younger brother or sister,
有个弟弟妹妹
our two families will thrive with prosperity,
将来咱们两家枝繁叶茂
and our entire clan
咱这一大家子
will be filled with such happiness.
得多幸福啊
What do you say?
你说呢
Let me ask you.
我问你
Did Mengxin
是不是你们家心心
say something to you?
跟你说什么了
No, she didn't.
心心能跟我说什么
What
你想心心
do you mean?
要跟我说什么呀
Nothing.
没事 没事 没事
Come on.
来
I'm
我呢
just very happy
就是高兴
as you're
你们要生二胎了
having a second child.
我替你们高兴
Come on, cheers.
来 喝酒喝酒
Lin,
姐夫
I'm sure you're hiding something.
你一定有事瞒着我
No.
不是
Look at me. Look at me.
看着我 看着我
Did the physical examination
姐是不是
reveal any other issues
检查身体的时候
of Meng'an?
查出了别的
Zhenzhen,
真真啊
why aren't you asleep yet?
怎么还不睡啊
What's wrong?
怎么了
I had to work overtime unexpectedly today,
妈妈今天临时加班
really couldn't back home early.
实在走不开
Sorry.
对不起啊
Mom.
妈妈
Could you not go to work anymore?
不要上班了好不好
Let's go back to Dad's home.
咱们回爸爸那里嘛
Good girl, Zhenzhen.
乖啊 真真
Mom promises you.
妈妈向你保证
I won't be back
下次啊
so late next time.
不会回来这么晚了
I'd prefer that you don't have to work.
妈妈还是不上班更好
You kids are off to school,
宝宝们去上学了
then mom will be boring
妈妈一个人在家
at home alone.
也没意思呀
Besides,
再说了
Mom needs to make money to support you.
妈妈要赚钱养你们
How about this, I promise to pick you up
这样 妈妈答应你们
after school tomorrow,
明天放学我去接
okay?
好不好
Well, bed time.
好 那快睡觉
Okay.
好
Keep your words, mom. Pinky swear.
那妈妈不许耍赖 拉钩
I give
拉钩上吊
my word.
一百年不许变
It's a deal.
盖章
All right, baby. Good night.
好嘞 宝贝晚安
Good night, mom.
妈妈晚安
I'm here to pick you up to go home.
我是来接你回家的
Yet you ask me to walk.
你非拉我来这儿溜达
We can enjoy the moon.
看看月亮呗
Not a good idea.
看什么月亮啊
I had a hard day at work.
你妈上一天班挺累的
It was cloudy all day long.
今天白天就阴天
Where is the moon?
哪儿有月亮啊
I can't see it.
哪儿呢
Just talk to me, okay?
你就陪我聊聊呗
Just have a chat.
聊聊嘛
Okay.
聊聊 聊聊
Let's have a chat.
聊聊
Great.
好
Oh.
对
Why do you carry candy with you?
怎么还随身带着糖啊
You have a bad appetite
你不是最近胃口不好
and throw up lately, right?
还老吐吗
Dad said
我听老爸说
it was due to low blood sugar.
你这是低血糖
So it's prepared for you.
所以就随身装了点啊
Wanna try it?
吃吗
Yeah.
吃
Sweet?
甜吗
Of course.
甜
Very sweet.
很甜
Mom,
老妈
I've got a question.
我问你个问题呗
Go ahead.
说
I heard that
我听说
women going through menopause
更年期的女人
are no longer able to conceive.
都没法再怀孕了
Is it true?
是真的吗
Why are you suddenly asking this?
怎么突然问这个呀
Just tell me the answer.
你就说是不是吧
I think so.
应该吧
I'm relieved.
那我就放心了
Why do you react like that?
怎么是这种反应啊
I was at He Lu's home today.
我今天在何璐家
I saw her dad yelling at her mom.
看到她爸吼她妈的
He was
样子了
so ferocious.
可凶啦
More ferocious than I yelled at your dad?
比我吼你爸还凶
Not the same.
不一样
Their quarrel was because of He Lu's grandma.
她们家是因为她奶奶
Her grandma took her three-year-old
她奶奶把她三岁的
brother back home.
弟弟带回来了
Her mother was agitated
因为理念不同
because of her grandma's different thoughts.
她妈就急了
Then her dad yelled at her mom.
然后她爸就吼她妈了
Which brother of her?
她哪个弟弟呀
Her biological brother!
亲弟弟呀
It's He Lu's secret.
我把何璐的秘密
But I said it out.
给说出来了
You've to keep it a secret.
你得替我保密啊
Secret?
保什么密啊
You said it out. Now explain to me.
说都说了 说全
He Lu's mom gave birth to a second child?
何璐她妈生二胎了
When did this happen?
什么时候的事啊
It's been a few years.
都好几年了
He Lu didn't know it at first.
何璐一开始都不知道呢
Poor her.
太可怜了她也
No wonder her family got a bigger apartment.
怪不得她们家换大房子
It was all planned.
这都是有预谋的呀
Since we moved into a bigger one,
咱们家换大房子
are you gonna...?
是不是也要
No.
不是
Absolutely not.
没有
So are you and Dad
那 你和老爸
planning
有没有准备
to have another baby?
再要一个宝宝
No plan.
没有准备
All right.
行
You are the only precious baby
妈和爸这辈子
of mom and dad.
就你这一个宝
I'm already 14 years old. You...
我都十四岁啦 你
But you're always my baby.
多大都是妈的宝
Do you truly not
就那么不想要
wish for siblings?
弟弟妹妹啊
You know,
怎么说呢
all I ever saw at He Lu's house
反正我在何璐家看到的
was utter chaos.
只有鸡飞狗跳
It made me headache.
吵得我脑袋都要裂开了
Truly annoying.
可闹心了
Thankfully, it won't happen in our family.
不过咱们家不会
You're going through menopause, aren't you?
你不都更年期了吗
Such things are unpredictable.
也不一定的
Then how high is the chance?
那几率大不大呀
Not likely.
不大
Good.
那就行
I'm relieved.
那就行啊
Some tonic for you.
今天厉害了
I cooked cubilose with milk.
牛奶燕窝
Where did you get it?
哪儿来的燕窝呀
Haowen gave it to me.
老贾送来的
I ate out with him
我跟他吃了个饭
and had some drinking.
还喝了点酒
He drank with you for unhappy things?
找你喝闷酒了
It's not what you think.
喝什么闷酒啊
He has happy things.
喜酒
Any happy event of them?
他有啥喜事啊
Mengxin got pregnant.
梦心不是怀二胎了吗
Haowen...
那老贾
on hearing of...
一听说
No, no.
不不不
Hadn't she become pregnant long before?
梦心不是早就怀了吗
What's wrong with you?
你什么情况
I'm drunken.
我喝多了
Right.
对
It's... he...
就是 他
Say it again.
你重说
Haowen got so excited
老贾一听说她
as he knew
马上就要生了
the baby's gonna be
别提有多激动
born soon.
多高兴了
That's it.
就这个事
Lin
要说我这个妹夫啊
is superb.
也是绝了
He is truly exceptional
这抗压能力
at coping with pressure.
真是比不了
Yes.
是
I even can't stand
就我那妹妹
Mengxin.
我都受不了
But he can.
你看人家
It's been hard for him.
老贾是真不容易啊
He's pretty awesome.
还是挺棒的
Didn't you originally find him
你原来不是
crude and lacking in refinement,
觉得他一身江湖气
reluctant to associate with him?
不太愿意跟他一块儿吗
Well...
这
Why did you drink together?
这怎么还喝上酒了呢
Vulgar and smooth as he is,
他一身江湖气
he still can be my friend.
也不妨碍和我做朋友
We get along well with each other.
我们有共同语言啊
Right?
对吧
Look at Haowen, such a great guy -
你看人家老贾多好啊
a big boss,
大老板
rich, successful in career,
有钱 有事业
and about to welcome his second baby soon.
现在马上有老二了
How wonderful!
多好呀
I'm really happy for him.
我替他高兴着呢
I'm jealous of him for you.
我替你酸着呢
Well, no, you...
这 不不不 你
I'm
我呀
actually regret it.
其实很后悔
I should have listened to you
就当初啊
back then.
我应该听你的劝
I should
我应该自己呀
make a good effort,
好好努努力
earn and save
多挣点钱
more money.
多存一点钱
Then we won't
不至于现在我们
be hard up
捉襟见肘的
and can't afford
连生个二胎
to give birth to a second baby.
都生不起
Right?
是吧
It's not
其实也不是
about the financial burden.
生得起生不起的事
What is it then?
那是什么事
Yunjie
云阶
felt me out today.
今天试探我
She asked me
问我说
if I wouldn't be able to have a second child
是不是更年期了
as I entered menopause.
就不能生二胎了
What does she mean?
她什么意思啊
She doesn't want a sibling.
就不想要弟弟妹妹呗
What did you say?
那你是怎么说的
I...
我
I just pacified her.
我就安抚呗
I said
表 表忠心
she's our only precious daughter.
说就她一个宝
Then...
后来
I'd to say
后 后来就被逼着承认
I'm nearly step in menopause.
快更年期了
So there's still room for change.
也算留了个口吧
That's good.
留了个口就好
Why?
好什么呀
Not good.
不好 不好 不好
I've been unsure to keep it or not.
本来就没想好要不要
The previous problem hasn't been sorted out,
老问题还没解决呢
yet a new one arises.
新问题就又来了
You didn't tell Haowen about this, right?
这事你没跟老贾说吧
No.
没有
I didn't.
没说
Keep it secret. Don't tell anyone.
别说 谁都别说
We
这事吧
have to think about the baby issue.
咱俩还是得好好想想的
Let's think it over.
好好想想
Drink it up.
喝吧
It's getting cold.
别凉了
I feel upset.
闹心了
How could you know it?
你怎么知道的
Did Lin tell you?
姐夫告诉你的
I guess it right?
真让我给猜着啦
Jia Haowen, you fox!
贾浩文 你诈我呢
Is she really pregnant?
姐怀二胎了
How dare you! Jia Haowen.
好你个贾浩文
You're quite cunning.
你跟我玩心眼了 是吧
Who told you that?
谁告诉你的
Say it!
说
You're not gonna sleep
你今天要不说
if you don't confess today.
别想睡觉
Dear, no one told me about it.
宝宝 没有人告诉我
I went to eat out with Lin.
我到姐夫那儿
I talked about you're having the second baby.
跟他说你怀二胎的事
But he spoke with hesitation,
但他鬼鬼祟祟
and tried to cover up something.
偷偷摸摸
I felt he had a secret.
我觉着他不对
Turns out I'm right!
让我给猜出来了
You're an outsider.
你一个外人
Don't mess with it.
你别瞎掺和
Meng'an doesn't want to have the baby.
我姐她不想生
Otherwise,
生了
her career is doomed to failure.
她的职业生涯就完了
Honey,
宝贝
it's not as terrible as you said.
没有你说得那么严重
The women in my company
我们公司那么多女同事
also need to bear a baby.
难道都不生孩子
Besides, she's already
再说了 姐已经干到了
a director.
总监的位置上
It won't affect it.
不影响
Bah!
呸
After I delivered Xiongxiong,
我生完熊熊之后
have I ever gone to work
六年了
for even a single day in these six years?
我上过一天班吗
Aren't you unwilling to go to work?
你不是不愿意上班吗
Don't I wanna go to work?
我不愿意上班
Or you tried
还是你想方设法
to stop me from getting employed?
不让我上班
Gently, please.
轻点 轻点 轻点
It's god's will.
那是天意
God makes you stay
老天爷注定你的命里
at home living in ease and comfort.
就应该是在家享清福
I'm gonna leave home for work tomorrow.
明天我就去上班
You stay home to take care of the kid.
你在家给我看孩子
No, no.
别别别
Darling,
宝贝
Please don't do this.
千万别啊
I go out
我就适合在外面
to fight in business battle,
冲锋陷阵
while you just
你就适合在咱们家
stay at home.
坚守阵地
You'll be the commander at home.
你就当那指挥官
The children and I will listen to your order.
以后我们爷仨听喝
We'll go to hit the target
你说往哪儿打
as you say.
我们就往哪儿冲
I hit you. I hit you!
我打你 我打你
I hit you!
我打你 打
I...
我
hit you!
打你
Now good things come
好事成双
in pairs.
双喜临门
That drink was truly worth it.
今天这酒真的没有白喝
I'll tell you what.
我告诉你啊
Keep out of it!
别掺和
So happy!
太高兴了
We're gonna have a large family.
人丁兴旺
How foolish this child would be
这孩子要随了你
to take after you!
那得多傻呀
Honey,
宝贝
of course the baby takes after you.
随你随你 孩子都随你
Today, your mom is taking a break,
今天你妈妈休息
and your dad is off to work.
爸爸上班
How about your dad drops you off at school?
我送你
Great!
好呀
I'm done with eating.
不吃了
Are you really that dissatisfied
你对我送你上学这个事
with me taking you to school?
那么不满意吗
Of course not.
满意
I really love it.
特别地满意
Time to go.
时间到了
Off now.
咱们走吧
Bye.
拜拜
Have you truly had enough?
不吃了
Leave the tableware for me.
吃完了你就放那儿啊
I'll clean them up when I get back.
我回来收拾
It's nice to be on the front passenger seat.
副驾的感觉就是好呀
Comfy?
舒服啊
Yeah.
舒服
Good.
好
That's great.
舒服就好
When you come of age,
等你成年了
I'll go with you for your driver's license test.
爸爸就带你去考驾照
You'll be driving the car.
到时候 你开着车
I'll be on the front passenger seat.
爸爸坐在副驾上
I can enjoy it, too.
我也享受享受
Okay.
行
Then
到时候
I'll drive to the place as you want.
你指哪儿我开哪儿
Stop at that milk tea shop ahead.
前面那奶茶店停一下
What do you want?
干什么
Buy a cup of milk tea.
买杯奶茶呀
Are you serious?
开玩笑呢
Do you remember your mom
你忘了你妈妈告诉你的
telling you not to eat in the car?
不许在车里吃东西
She is not here.
她不是不在吗
But you still can't do this.
不在也不行
Do you remember
对
when I took you
上回
to have fried chicken
我带着你去吃炸鸡
in the car?
在车里
You were happily enjoying it,
是吧 你吃得高兴
but I had to spend ages to remove the smell.
我扇味扇了半天
Yet the moment your mom got into the car,
回头你妈一上车
she detected the scent
就闻到味了
and
劈头盖脸地
gave me an earful.
把我说了一通啊
But the milk tea is odorless.
奶茶没味啊
What if it spills
那万一洒到车里
in the car?
怎么办啊
I promise it won't happen.
我保证 绝对不会洒的
No way.
那不行
Please?
爸
No.
不行
I promise I'm not gonna spill it.
我真的不会洒的
Then you'd be careful later.
那你一会儿小心点
I'll drive slowly, too.
我也慢点开
Excellent!
行
Having a dad like you,
有你这样的父亲
I'm so lucky!
真是我的幸运
Fine, fine.
行行行
What am I gonna do with you?
又来这套
Which shop?
哪家
The one in front.
就前面那个
[That one, right?]
那个是吧
Yes.
对对对
[Okay.]
好好好
I'm here!
这儿呢
Come on!
加油
Ten meters to go.
还有十米
The scene is good here.
景是不错
But I'm exhausted.
就是有点累
How could this happen?
是怎么回事呢
How many breaks did you take in between?
你中间歇了几趟啊
Five times.
五趟
Given over 400 steps, it's reasonable.
四百多的台阶 得五趟
Good. You know how to look after yourself.
还行 还知道照顾自己
But to be honest,
但是说实话啊
you lack physical strength.
你啊 这体力太差了
You don't get enough exercise.
你就缺乏锻炼
You know?
你知道吗
You've got weak legs.
腿没力气
You're trying to take me
你这是想带我
climb high and look far?
登高望远啊
Are you gonna discuss with me
今天要说的事
for something serious?
是不是有点大
Yeah, I would like to ask you for a favor.
我还真有事请你帮忙
Then you go ahead,
那你先说
I'll catch my breath first.
让我先喘口气
Okay, get some water.
来 喝口水啊
I'm gonna
我呢
hold a real estate trade show.
准备办一个看房会
Just introduce to me anyone you know
你身边有没有能买房的
who are capable of or interested in purchasing a house.
想买房的 都推荐给我
Real estate trade show?
看房会啊
I wish my apartment
早知道我那房
hasn't been bought.
晚两年买就好了
Otherwise, I might even get a discount from you.
没准还能落一折扣
There's no discount,
折扣倒没有啊
but you can save on some property management fees.
但是能省点物业
I already negotiated it with the salesman.
这个我跟他们谈了
You're selling it like hot cakes.
你这房卖得如火如荼啊
Doesn't Yu Hai have a problem with that?
于海 就没啥意见吗
You were classmates.
你跟他是老同学
I bet you know him well.
你还不了解他吗
So are you gonna
那你这是打算
go against him?
叛逆到底了
I've to work.
我得开单呀
I've to earn money to support my children.
我得挣钱养孩子呀
Yu Hai has entrusted his lawyer
于海的律师都已经
to fight me for custody.
跟我争抚养权了
What should I do?
你说我该怎么办
No way.
不会吧
Yu Hai won't be so mean.
于海不像这种人哪
Yeah.
是啊
I know he just tries to scare me.
我知道他在吓唬我
He always thought that
他呢
I wasn't serious about divorcing him,
总觉得我这次在开玩笑
and when I get bored,
闹够了
I'll go back home.
就回家了
But this time,
但是我这一次
I truly want to tell him that
真的想告诉他
I am serious about the divorce.
我离婚就是真的
I'm not kidding.
我不是在闹着玩的
He doesn't
他这领悟力
understand what you mean.
有点差了
Not just him.
不光是他
Many friends around me
我身边好多朋友
think I'm joking.
都以为我在开玩笑呢
They think you're playing tricks
觉得你在耍手段
to teach your husband a lesson.
给老公个教训
To be frank,
说实话开始的时候
that's what I was thinking at first.
我也是这么想的
Come on!
去去去
You don't know me well either.
你太不靠谱了
But you asked me to help you
但是后来
find a job later,
你让我帮你找工作
then I knew
我就知道
you meant it.
你是要动真格的了
Have you made any preparations
办看房会
for the trade show?
做没做点准备啊
It's all ready.
都准备好了
I made
我呢
a presentation.
做了一份演示文稿
Please help me review it.
你帮我看一下啊
I don't think one presentation is convincing.
一份演示文稿不太行吧
How about
要不回头
I send our presentations
我把我们那些
for real estate clients
地产客户的演示文稿
for your reference?
都发你参考参考
Great.
好啊
You can't just sell them.
咱不能只开单哪
You must be the top sales.
咱得当销冠哪
You truly live up to the title of Content Director.
不愧是内容总监
Impressive.
厉害
We can't go up here for nothing.
不能白登高啊
We are here for a broader view.
得望远啊
[Hi, Mrs. Yu.]
于太太
Hi, Mrs. Wang.
王太太你好
It's been a long time.
好久不见了
You can see
我们可以看到
we have...
我们现在手里有
Hi ladies,
各位太太们
you're in such a good mood today.
今天心情这么好啊
Learning flower arrangement, huh?
学插花是吗
Hi, Mrs. Yu.
于太太
Long time no see.
好久不见了
Wu Tong, you've lost weight.
吴彤 你瘦了
Mrs. Mo,
莫太太
you look elegant today.
你今天好漂亮啊
Wanzhen,
婉真
Did you actually move?
你真搬家啦
Right.
对呀
Why did you move out suddenly?
你怎么突然就搬走了呢
I hear from Mr. Yu that
我听于总说
you're doing some business all by yourself.
你一个人在外面干大事
That's why
是不是就把家
you moved to the city, I guess.
搬到城里去啦
My relationship with him
我跟于海的关系
isn't the same as before.
最近有一点点变化
You already have two kids,
你都两个孩子了
are you truly considering a divorce,
怎么 你真像外面说的
as others said?
要离婚哪
Wanzhen,
婉真
be sure to act wisely.
你可别犯傻
Mr. Yu's career soars.
小于总现在正是上升期
If you divorce him now,
你现在跟他离婚
another woman
那不是便宜了
would take the advantage.
别的女人哪
Don't worry.
放心吧
I've been though it through.
这件事情我想了很久了
I'll fight for custody of the kid,
我会争取孩子的抚养权
getting ready
将来的生活
for the future too.
我也在做准备着
Is he cheating?
他是不是在外面有人了
Let's change the topic.
今天不说这些了
I'm coming today
我今天来呢
to invite all of you
是邀请大家
for our company's wine party.
参加我们公司的酒会
Here is the invitation for you.
这是邀请函
Why did Mrs. Yu come back?
这于太太回来干吗呀
Mrs. Yu?
什么于太太呀
Better not to call her Mrs. Yu right now.
现在还说不定呢
You've no idea about it?
你不知道呀
She moved out
她带着孩子
with her kids.
都搬出去了
Divorced?
离婚了
Oh, there's another one got divorced.
又多了一个浩泽妈妈呀
Who knows what happens?
谁知道呢
We're not sure about
他们俩怎么样
their current relationship,
我们也不清楚
right?
是不是
It's not our business.
不管
Holding wine parties to sell houses?
现在卖房子都办酒会了
Here you go, Mrs. Wu.
来来来 吴太太
[Right.]
对呀
Mrs. Chen.
陈太
Oh.
怎么
You really went to this firm
你还真去这家公司
to sell real estate?
做房产销售去了
Yeah, I've worked there for a short time.
是啊 刚做没多久
By the way,
对了
Xu Mengxin in our community
咱们小区许梦心
also bought one from me
也在我那儿买了一套
for investment.
投资用的房
I'll set aside
到时候呢
the best house type
我会给大家留出
for you.
最好的户型
You guys have to come!
你们一定要来啊
Be sure to come!
一定要来啊
Okay, we'll go together then.
好 我们到时候一起去
That's for sure.
必须的
Besides selling the property,
除了卖房呢
this wine party
这个酒会啊
will also feature
还有一个
a personal segment about me.
关于我自己的小环节
I'll explain
就是
my current relationship
我会跟大家说明一下
with Yu Hai.
我跟于海之间的关系
It's a press conference.
记者发布会
It won't be that big.
不至于了
You guys
你看你们
usually concern a lot about me.
平时那么关心我
I guess you wanna know
也很好奇
what really goes on between me and him.
我跟于海的小秘密
That will save you
省得你们天天
the guess.
猜来猜去的
I'll invite Mr. Yu over
到时候这个酒会呢
on this wine party.
我会邀请于先生过来
And then I'll explain
然后跟大家详细说一下
what happens between us.
我跟他之间的事
What's going on with you and him?
你跟于总到底怎么了
Why is it that
为什么要闹到
you get a divorce?
离婚的地步呀
Mrs. Mo,
莫太太
you'll know it
你来参加酒会了
in the party.
就知道了
All right.
好了
I'm leaving.
那我先走了
You can continue with the flower arrangement.
你们好好插花
Leaving so soon?
这就走了
Yeah.
对
Bye.
拜拜
Are you up yet?
起了吗
Don't get me started.
你别提了
I'm lying in bed now,
我现在躺在床上呀
unable to sleep
睡嘛 也睡不着
or even get up.
起吧 也起不来
It's utterly miserable.
难受死了
What's wrong?
怎么了
[I've got an aching waist]
腰又酸
[and numb legs.]
腿又麻
I just don't feel well lying down.
怎么躺都不得劲
Are you calling me for anything?
你找我什么事啊
Nothing important.
也没什么大事
How do you...
就是
feel about
我想问问你
the private
你现在去的那个
maternity hospital
私立妇产医院
you're attending now?
怎么样啊
Why do you ask?
你干吗
Have you decided to deliver the baby?
你又要生啊
No.
也不是
I'm in a vacation now.
就是现在不是休假了吗
[I'm concerned that if]
我想着要是
[I opt for abortion surgery at a public hospital,]
手术去公立医院的话
[I might not]
可能
secure an appointment in time.
挂不上号 时间来不及
I hope to know more of the hospital you visit.
想问问你那边什么情况
You startled me!
你吓死我了
You know what.
我跟你说
If you give birth to this child,
你要是生
the same misery will come upon you.
就是我现在这个后果
[Even worse,]
不
[you'll suffer even more at your age.]
你高龄产妇 更遭罪
Stop it.
行了
Just tell me about the hospital.
说正事
It's a nice place.
那地方条件挺好的
I'll ask
回头我给你问问
my attending doctor about it.
我的主治大夫
Okay.
行
Please ask for me.
那你帮我问问吧
By the way,
对了
guess what?
你知道吗
[Haowen knows you're pregnant.]
老贾知道你怀孕了
You told it to him?
你跟他说的
Absolutely not me!
我没有说
He figured it out by himself.
那他 那他自己猜的
Lin ate with him.
这 姐夫跟他吃饭
Lin is not the one to lie.
这姐夫又不会撒谎
You two really gossipy.
你们这两口子可真行啊
You two
不是一家人
are just similar.
不进一家门
[Both of you act like paparazzi.]
都挺有做狗仔的潜质啊
Listen up.
我跟你讲
You must make it clear to Jia Haowen that
你跟贾浩文给我说清楚
this cannot be mentioned to our parents,
这事千万不能告诉爸妈
got it?
知道吗
You are right,
对对对
I'll remind him right away.
我赶紧提醒他
Or
不然啊
he'd try to impress my mom
他为了讨好丈母娘
by telling it to her.
什么事都做得出来
I... I'll call him right now.
我 我给他打电话啊
[Bye.]
挂了
Haowen...
浩文
Hire me?
聘我
Does Mengxin know it?
心心知道吗
No.
不知道啊
But
心心不知道
you've got the nerve to tell me this?
你都敢直接跟我说了
Meng'an, let me explain.
姐 是这样的
My company
我们公司呀
needs to hire
现在要聘一个
a consultant on new media.
新媒体方面的顾问
Select the worthy without avoiding relatives.
举贤不避亲
The annual salary is CNY 200,000.
年薪二十万
You're the right one for this post.
我觉得您特别合适
A consultant?
顾问
Twenty thousand for
还是个兼职
a part-time consultant?
给二十万
Meng'an,
姐
I think you're worth of the pay.
我觉着您太值了
Really.
真的
Looks like you're giving me money.
你这就是给我钱呢
Meng'an,
姐
I may be
我跟你说吧
older than you.
我虽然年纪比你大
But I'm your brother-in-law.
但怎么也是您妹夫呢
I know there is something
有些话呢
I shouldn't mention to you.
我是不该开口的
But
但是呢
I recently found something I'd to say.
我最近有一个发现
What is it?
发现什么了
I think Lin has something
我觉得最近我看姐夫啊
on his mind lately.
心里老有事
He looks a little glum.
有点闷闷不乐的样子
This must be what you truly intended to
这是你今天找我
discuss with me today, isn't it?
真正想说的内容吧
Indeed, you intellectuals
你说你这知识分子
are just smart.
就是聪明啊
I haven't even said it
我还没说呢
yet you already understand.
你就明白了
Just tell me.
说吧
Meng'an,
姐
we've been all
你说咱们
working very hard.
工作什么都挺累的哈
It's all
为什么
for the sake of our families.
不都是为了这个家吗
Don't you wanna think
生孩子的事 您就
about giving birth to the baby?
不愿意再多想想啊
The fetus
这肚里的孩子
is like a little bud,
他像一个小芽儿一样
and will grow up over months.
他几个月就慢慢地长大
Soon, the baby will be born.
这孩子就生出来了
From the moment of birth,
一生下来
there will be tears and smiles,
会哭会笑
and later the baby grows to play.
大了会打会闹
In the future, the child cares for you
将来还能心疼你
and calls you Mom.
管你叫妈
What a bliss!
多好啊
Meng'an,
姐
just talk with me for any worries.
有什么事 您就跟我说
We are families.
咱是一家人
[I know you're the decision-maker in your family.]
我知道 你们家你主事
[But have you ever]
可生孩子这事
[given a thought to]
你有没有想过
[Lin's idea about keeping the baby?]
姐夫是咋想的呢
Allow me to consider this question
那我斗胆地
from the viewpoint of my brother-in-law.
替姐夫想一下
Because I think
因为我觉得
we're just alike.
我跟他特别像
[I grew up with only my widowed mother,]
我从小我们家孤儿寡母
[and his parents passed away]
他从小呢
[when he was a little child.]
父母很早就没了
[I know]
我知道
[neither of us has a big family.]
我们两家都是人丁不旺
He'll surely
你有没有想过姐夫
wish to have
他肯定希望世上
one more kid.
多一个他的亲人嘛
[Well, if you'll give birth]
那你要是跟心心
[to a second baby as Mengxin,]
都生二胎
Mom and Dad would be so happy
那咱一回家这一大家子
to see the big family when we back home.
那爸妈得多高兴
The children play at the yard
这过年了
at the Spring Festival.
孩子满院地跑
The elder ones
这姐姐哥哥
lead their younger siblings
带着弟弟妹妹
as kids love to play together.
孩子们就爱一起玩
How happy they'd be!
多高兴啊
You know,
那我跟心心
when I was dating with Mengxin,
当时谈对象的时候
every time I upset her,
我一惹她 她就说
she'd say,
我找我姐去
I would argue, "it was between us,
我说咱俩的事
why do you keep involving your sister?"
你老跟你姐说什么啊
Then she would explain that
她说我姐
you are like a heroine.
是飞机中的战斗机
And if I dared to make her upset,
你敢惹我
you'd stand up for her.
我姐替我出头
Besides,
还有啊
Xiongxiong also said to Xin,
我们家熊熊也跟妈妈说
"Mom, have another brother for me,
妈 你再给我生个弟弟
so when bad kids mess with me,
那将来坏孩子惹我
and beat us up,
我俩一起挨揍
the two of us can stand up for each other."
还能一起上手呢
As long as Mengxin agrees,
这心心要是愿意
I'm ready
我就愿意
to have more kids,
生一大家子孩子
so many that our family portrait
这我们再拍全家福
won't be able to contain us all in one frame.
一个照片都框不下
Isn't it great, Meng'an?
多好啊 姐
I think it's a kind of happiness.
我觉得这叫幸福
Mengxin may not give birth to so many babies.
心心可能不会生那么多
Haowen.
浩文啊
What you said
你说的这些呢
is reasonable.
都对
I agree with you.
我也都认同
But my family doesn't
但是我们家情况
run like yours.
跟你们家不一样
You all know that
你们都知道
I'm the decision maker in my family.
我们家是我主事
But our financial stuff
但是财务方面的事情呢
is in the hands of Lin.
都是你姐夫管
I know you mean well.
我知道你是好心啊
You wanna lend me a hand,
想帮我
offering me this part-time work,
找我做兼职
but
但是
it puts me in an awkward position.
我挺尴尬的
Don't get me wrong.
我没有别的意思啊
I just say what I feel.
就是打个比方
Today I feel embarrassed
你跟我说这一次
hearing your offer.
我也就尴尬一回
Have you ever considered
但是你有没有想过
the position Lin would be in
如果我每次把这个钱
if I were to give him the money every time?
都拿给你姐夫的时候
what'd he feel?
他会是什么样
When he spends the money,
他每次花这个钱的时候
he'd be overthinking.
又会想些什么
If this becomes a regular occurrence,
长此以往下去
Lin...
你姐夫
I can't say for sure
我不知道他这个状态
how long he can maintain this state.
能持续多久啊
But he certainly cannot make it now.
但是现在肯定是不行
If what I just said
如果真像
happens,
我刚才说的那样
our family
那我们这个家
won't have democracy and equality.
就谈不上什么民主平等
It will be out of balance.
它会失衡的
How can we
那又怎么能
call it happiness?
说得上是幸福呢
As a man,
你作为一个男人
you should understand
我说的这些
what I've said.
你应该都懂的
Right?
是吧
Or you can
要不你
engage in the medical business.
进军一下医疗产业
Get Lin a job.
给你姐夫找个工作
Meng'an,
姐
you are kidding me.
你别逗我 这我哪儿会
That's a completely new industry to me.
这隔着行呢 这个
Let's see how it goes.
再等等吧
Mr. Li.
李老师
The procedure is complete.
这个手续都完成了
Just have the dean
您找院长呢
sign here,
在这儿签个字
then all is done.
就可以了
Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢
Never mind, Mr. Li.
李老师 您太客气了
We're all gonna work together.
咱以后都是同事
Yeah, right.
是是 以后都是同事了
You can just call my name.
就不用称呼我老师了
Mr. Li,
李老师
the dean's office
那个 院长办公室呢
is on the east side of the fourth floor.
就在四楼 东头
Got it, all right.
四楼东头 好 好
I'll go by myself.
我自己去就行了
Okay.
那你 好嘞好嘞
Bye, Mr. Li
那再见啊 李老师
Bye.
再见 再见 再见
Mr. Ma,
不是 马院长
You are aware of
我的学术能力
my academic ability.
您是了解的呀
Dr. Ji,
季博士
it's not that I won't help you.
不是我不帮你
You know the college's policy
学院的留校政策
to hire a teacher.
你是知道的呀
[You're not releasing enough papers]
你这论文数发得不够
[nor significant academic accomplishments.]
也没什么学术成果
[I really can't keep you here.]
我实在是没办法留你啊
My kid is still young.
可是我们家孩子还小
frequently falls ill,
他还总是生病
[and with his father away,]
他爸爸又在外地
[I must]
我得一个人
[care for him by myself.]
照顾孩子的呀
Dr. Ji,
季博士
if you're
你现在这个状态
still like this,
如果再不改变的话
you won't be qualified for academic research.
也不适合搞学术了
I'll figure something out for you.
我再帮你想想办法
Look.
你说说你
I had the most confidence in you.
当初我是最看好你的
Mr. Ma.
马院长
Please come in.
请进
Li Lin.
李临
Come in!
来来来
Are all the formalities done?
手续都办好了吗
Yeah.
办好了
All I need is your signature now.
就差您签个字了
You've seen that female doctor.
刚才那个女博士
I thought she could
我当初还以为她能
be successful just like Mei Yiduo.
成梅一朵第二呢
[But during these two years]
可是这两年呢
[she's not even focusing on academics.]
心思都不在学术上了
Mei Yiduo works really hard.
梅一朵 真是拼啊
She is even divorced for her academic developments.
为了搞学术 婚都离了
You know it?
你听说了吗
She'll be back soon.
她快回来了
I'm planning
我想
to invite this famous scientist
把这个明星科学家
to our college.
请到咱们学院来
[I'm gonna]
这个重任
[leave it to you.]
我可要交给你了啊
Now that you've found a job,
工作的事情都办完了
shouldn't we be heading home
不是应该回家
to celebrate it?
庆祝一下吗
Why do you bring me up here?
带我上这儿坐着干吗呀
My business is done.
我的事办完了
Now I wanna talk to you
我想跟你
about the baby.
聊聊孩子的事啊
You asked me
那天晚上你问我
if I wanted the baby or not that night.
想不想要
I said yes.
我说我想要
It was an instinctive reaction.
那是本能反应
In fact, we've been deliberately
其实这两天我们俩
avoiding to face this problem
都在刻意地回避
in the past few days.
这个问题
That's because
那是因为
it is indeed
这的确
worthy of us
是值得我们
giving it a careful consideration.
好好考虑的事情
I know
我也知道
you
你对这个孩子
love the baby.
不是没有感情
But my dear,
但是老婆
you only think about the present.
你考虑的是现在
But I worry about the future.
而我犹豫的是将来
Over the past decade or so,
过去的十几年里
we've both worked hard
我们两个很努力
to live
好不容易才过上
a better life.
现在这样的日子
But now if we have another kid,
如果我们再生一个
our family may
将来十年
go through
甚至更久
hard life again
我们全家可能
in the next decade
又要过一遍
or even longer.
这样紧紧巴巴的日子
I'm not afraid of the hardship.
我不怕吃苦
I can cope with it.
我 我怎么样都行的
I know you can go it through too.
我知道你也可以吃苦
However,
但是
I can't let you and Yunjie
我不能够让你和云阶
suffer with me
再跟着我
again.
吃一遍苦吧
So,
所以
it seems we may not
这个孩子
be meant to have this child.
可能跟我们没有缘分了
I can't give birth to a second baby
家里这种情况
given our financial situation.
也没法要啊
Raising one child is already challenging,
养一个孩子还都
let alone two.
何况养两个呢
You're unemployed now,
你现在失业
and I'm pregnant, staying at home.
然后我怀孕在家待产
How can we
家里吃什么
make a living?
喝什么
Pick a day
找个时间
to get the surgical abortion done.
去把手术做了
I can't let us
我不能够让全家人
live in hardships all the time.
一直这样吃着苦过日子
So,
所以
it seems we may not
这个孩子可能
be meant to have this child.
跟我们没有缘分了
He'll surely
你有没有想过姐夫
wanna have
他肯定希望世上
one more kid.
多一个他的亲人嘛
What's up?
怎么了
In a bad mood?
心情不好啊
I want to climb high
想登个高
and see far.
望个远
What's going on?
到底怎么了
I've discussed with Li Lin.
我跟李临商量好了
We've decided
这个孩子
not to have this child.
不要了
Why?
为什么
We cannot afford it.
养不起
We have cancelled Yunjie's Piano lessons.
云阶钢琴课都停了
Although her teacher said
虽然老师说她
she won't make achievement on it,
不会有什么成就
her father and I know that
但我跟她爸都知道
she still wants to learn it.
孩子还想学
If we have enough money...
但凡我们有点能力
If we have to raise another baby,
要是再要一个孩子的话
the life
以后日子
will be harder.
还不知道过成什么样
I'm over forty years old.
活了四十多岁了
yet I feel very helpless now.
突然觉得很无力
I get
你说的
what you said.
我懂
Raising a child
现在养孩子
is not a matter of making him survival now.
不是活不活的问题
Instead, it's about
而是
how to raise the child well.
怎么能把孩子养得好
[It's not because of a desire to compete,]
倒不是攀比啊
but the love that we hold for children.
而是父母的那一颗心
Let's see
日子
how it goes.
还得往前走着看